♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we pass by the magnificent scenery ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Could it be that both of us
are filled with desolation? ♪
♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we lead such a life ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Turning back, you and I ♪
♪ Seize the current moment ♪
♪ The sky is painted
with a gentle pallet of pastel colors ♪
♪ Let's walk together ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ The snow in front of us ♪
♪ Will dye our hair white ♪
♪ In an instant ♪
[Joy of Life Season 2]
[Adapted from Mao Ni's Joy of Life
on Yuewen Group's Qidian platform]
[Episode 28]
I can't believe
such a hand cannon does exist.
This is different.
Young Lady brought it out.
From where?
Divine Temple.
She brought this from the Divine Temple?
Yet, the main component is missing.
It's damaged.
Who damaged it?
You don't need to know that.
The only thing you need to do is
to learn this
and protect Fan Xian.
And?
Can you fix it?
Not me.
Protecting Fan Xian
is a secret.
I won't tell anyone.
Not even to Xian?
Yes.
But why me?
What matters the most to you
in this world?
Xian, of course.
And that's the reason why.
He just left like that?
Do you understand what Mr. Fan said?
Me neither.
See you tonight.
I'm leaving.
Hurry.
See you later.
See you then.
What's it about?
I saw those merchants releasing pigeons
out there.
I'm curious,
so I caught one.
Did they send this to the Capital?
They informed them
about what happened here.
Why?
Aren't they the owners
of their business?
Can't they decide on their own
whether or not to buy the treasury bonds?
How could a rootless tree
stand on its own?
Are you saying that they have backing?
Apparently.
Well, I will release it.
Don't dissect the pigeon.
All right?
Fan Sizhe, you were impressive.
You were talking in front of everyone.
Of course.
Ruoruo,
let me tell you this.
It's true that Fan Xian's idea
is stupendous.
It's totally new to me.
But you should look at it this way.
Even I have never heard of them,
how would those merchants understand?
Those terms Fan Xian mentioned
like "national prospect"
and "wealth".
Those officials
and merchants can't fathom the concept.
The only term to impress them is
"royalty".
You are happy about this.
Of course I am.
Still,
I feel that something is missing,
which worries me.
What are you worried about?
At first, I thought
they would be intimidated
by the very mention of His Majesty
and would hand over their money.
But you see,
they sent messages back to the Capital.
What's wrong with that?
The treasury bonds
have never been done before.
I'm afraid
this goes against the state law.
Don't worry about that.
Well, good.
You led the second half.
You gave them an absolute promise.
If anything happens,
you will take the fall.
He couldn't be plotting this, could he?
I was helping him.
Gosh.
No.
That's impossible.
We are quite close now.
Right, he won't do this to me.
The treasury bonds
aren't considered illegal, right?
Of course they are.
Treasury bonds?
I have never heard of this
since the founding of the Qing State.
He is utterly a rebellious brat!
Sharing the burden of the imperial debt,
he says?
Such absurdity!
This is against the state law!
As the saying goes,
"Parents are to blame
for children's mistakes."
I suggest
escorting Fan Xian back
and removing me from my position.
With a mischievous son like him,
I'm too ashamed to remain an official.
I might as well resign
and return to Danzhou.
Mr. Chen, wake up.
Why wake me up when you are lashing out?
Tell us
about your view on treasury bonds.
I don't have any views.
Are you blind?
The Imperial Treasury isn't under
the Imperial Inspectorate's supervision.
I can't do anything about it.
We are not talking
about the Imperial Treasury.
It's the treasury bonds.
That's new.
I have never heard of that.
Indeed.
The treasury bonds
have never been heard of since ancient.
According to the law of the Qing State,
there aren't any terms concerning
the treasury bonds.
No laws could be based on
if he were to be punished.
Such novelty.
What do you think about this, Chengze?
Your Highness,
I'm still grounded for reflection.
Without His Majesty's summon,
I wouldn't dare step out of the room,
let alone intervene in state affairs.
It's fine. Just speak up.
No laws
or reasons to be based on,
only His Majesty could decide.
You are all here.
Please come with me.
Where is His Majesty?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Then where are you taking us to?
The Imperial Garden.
Why are we going to the harem's garden
in the middle of the night?
To transplant flowers.
Eunuch Hou.
Are you sure
this is His Majesty's order?
Mr. Fan,
I would never dare
fabricate orders from His Majesty.
What exactly is going on?
Just transplanting the flowers.
Only a few of us?
Where are the servants?
His Majesty banned the servants
from entering
this area.
Mr. Fan, thank you for your hard work.
The Chrysanthemum Festival
is held every three years.
It was held
at the Hanging Temple, right?
Indeed.
These are just ordinary flowers.
Why do we have
to deliver them personally?
His Majesty likes them.
His Majesty is telling us
that he cares
about the Chrysanthemum Festival.
But why is he telling us now?
I remember the festival
in previous years
weren't held at this time.
It's rescheduled.
Until when?
Just recently.
We have to wait
for the exact date.
What are we waiting for?
We have to wait
until Mr. Fan returns from Mount Cang.
Why do we need to wait for him
before deciding the date?
This is what His Majesty said.
His Majesty values
the Chrysanthemum Festival,
but the date will be announced
only after Fan Xian returns.
That's right, Your Highness.
His Majesty is trying to remind us
that the Chrysanthemum Festival
is important,
but Fan Xian
is more important.
Did you leave it in the Capital?
I carried it from the carriage myself
and put it in your room.
A big box
couldn't just vanish into thin air.
What's inside the box?
It's from the Divine Temple.
The Divine Temple?
Is it some powerful weapon?
It is if the components are complete.
Does it miss a piece?
The main component is missing.
Nothing is missing in this room.
Only the box disappeared.
It means the person who took it
knows what is inside.
Not many know about this.
Who's there?
Mr. Fan,
someone is there!
Good skills.
I didn't even notice.
Wang, protect Wan'er.
Yes.
Master.
My dear.
Commander Jing?
Haven't you got back to the encampment?
Black Cavalries are ordered
to stand guard at Mount Cang
and protect you.
Shadow?
Wang Qinian is quite cautious.
Turns out
it's the Imperial Inspectorate.
Is this a team building event?
What is team building?
We always have novel terms here.
Just get used to it.
Master,
what brings you to Mount Cang?
Because you are here.
Mr. Fan,
did you lose anything?
You were eavesdropping on us.
I think Mr. Wu does it.
What do you mean?
He has been secretly following you
and waiting for a chance
to spar with Mr. Wu.
Mr. Fan,
you are his disciple.
Why don't we
have a match?
Stay still
or I will poison you.
There is nothing else here, right?
I think so.
Retreat.
Just ignore us.
Forget I exist.
What's wrong with them?
So secretive.
Let's go, Master.
You have come to Mount Cang,
let's get supper at my place.
Sorry, it's this way.
Hold on.
I have to tell you something.
I went to Jiangnan for a murder case.
The murderer disappeared
after he arrived in the Capital.
Two possibilities.
Either it's Mr. Wu...
What is the other possibility?
Someone hid this murderer
in the Capital.
Not even the Imperial Inspectorate
could track him down.
Of course,
only a few in the Capital
are capable of that.
Well, this is also a clue.
I came here to spend some days with you.
This case spooks me.
I will follow up on this
after returning to the Capital.
I was planning to meet up with you
after getting the result.
I will lie low for now.
Master.
You have almost cured
Wan'er's lung disease.
Give this to her.
Take one pill every day.
She will recover
by the time she finishes these.
I wish you a happy marriage.
This is what His Majesty and I
are eager to see.
You should resign.
I will look after you.
Nonsense.
I'm serious.
Enough of that.
A grandmaster is hiding in the Capital.
I won't rest
until I find him.
Master.
Enough of nagging.
Hurry and have a child.
I will teach him poisoning skills
when he grows up.
I'm off.
Promise me.
Don't take risks.
Don't worry.
I'm more afraid of dying than you.
Mr. Wuzhu?
You took the box.
Come with me.
Wait... Have you been sitting here?
No one sees you?
It makes sense.
You are different.
Mr. Wuzhu,
it seems Shadow is interested in you.
He always expects a spar with you.
I'm not interested.
What are you looking for?
Is there something inside here?
Young Lady stayed in Mount Cang for a while.
My mother hid this?
It should've been destroyed,
just like this box.
My mother destroyed this?
Why?
To observe the law.
Anything ahead of its time
shouldn't remain.
Whose law?
The Divine Temple's?
Maybe.
Maybe?
I forgot.
If that's the case,
why didn't she destroy all these?
And why did she leave behind
these three things?
Anything ahead of its time
shouldn't remain in this reset world.
History mustn't be affected.
But you are different.
You are a mistake.
A mistake?
You belong to both this world
and the past.
You are a mistake,
a glitch,
an unknown variable,
and a flawed logic.
That's what Young Lady said.
Did part of my memories
come from the Divine Temple?
I don't know.
I'm just restating her words.
What Young Lady left for you
is a chance to survive.
Fix it
and you will have three chances
to change your destiny.
How to fix it?
Go to Jiangnan.
Go to the Three Great Workshops.
The Three Great Workshops
are the foundation
of the Imperial Treasury.
Everyone knows that.
The Imperial Treasury used to base
on the Three Great Workshops.
All those novel things in the past
came from Jiangnan.
Do you know
who owns the Three Great Workshops now?
The Ming family in Jiangnan, of course.
The Ming family has always followed
the Eldest Princess.
I doubt they would hand over
the Three Great Workshops.
Even though
they are affluent in Jiangnan,
they dare not defy the decree.
They won't, for sure.
What to hand over
and how?
It has its own rules.
I suppose we merchants
are well aware of that.
In that case,
it's very unlikely for Fan Xian
to take over the Imperial Treasury.
That's right.
Let's not fall into his trap.
How will he repay us
if we buy the treasury bonds?
You are right.
We won't buy them.
If so,
let's leave first thing in the morning.
Whoever buys them is a jerk.
Yes.
Whoever buys them is a jerk!
Jerk.
Come on.
Let's drink.
This is a product beyond our time.
What exactly is
in the Three Great Workshops?
How do they manage to fix this?
You will find out when you get there.
I'm going to Jiangnan anyhow.
I must retrieve
my mother's property.
Why didn't she put them together
in this box?
Young Lady left this for you,
but she didn't want you
to have it fixed.
Why?
When the Divine Temple
alters someone's destiny,
the future will leave its mark.
That doesn't make sense to me.
If the items of the Divine Temple
are overly used,
you will eventually end up
in the Divine Temple.
This sounds rather surreal.
I will wait
until you arrive in Jiangnan.
You will only grow the courage
to face the Grandmasters by then.
Isn't it unfair
to use it against Grandmasters?
Not really.
What does that mean?
I might not defeat Grandmasters
even with this?
Exactly.
Grandmasters are human.
How can they possibly dodge
such an advanced weapon?
Do you think I'm normal?
Grandmasters
aren't held back
by the usual limitations.
Doesn't that make them monsters?
Pretty much so.
News from the palace says
that His Majesty summons Fan Xian back
for the Chrysanthemum Festival.
What about the treasury bonds?
His Majesty didn't mention that.
Have you heard about that?
The Chrysanthemum Festival?
That's not important.
His Majesty waits for Fan Xian
probably because he writes good poems.
Yes, you are right.
His literary talents aren't good enough
to handle the Imperial Treasury.
Exactly.
Where are you going?
Well,
I'm going to the loo.
I always go for a walk after waking up.
Please go ahead.
See you later.
Oh, it's this way.
Didn't you go for a walk?
Is this the loo?
Oh, my.
How did you end up here from a walk?
It must be the right choice.
You...
Mr. Fan,
remember to reserve
50,000 taels of bonds
for me.
I'm heading back to get money.
I will come back later.
Why are you here too?
Did you forget what you said yesterday?
He's a jerk.
And this jerk
bought the treasury bonds.
I'm leaving.
Take a rest.
[Treasury Bonds]
Thanks.
Wan'er, wipe your hands.
Xian, the figure doesn't match up.
Maybe someone
didn't bring enough banknotes
and go home to get some.
I did a rough calculation.
It's more than 20 million taels.
The bonds are limited
and sold at a premium price.
It's all thanks to you
to sell them off.
The treasury bonds are sold off.
Why are you unhappy?
They bought the treasury bonds
because His Majesty invited me
to the Chrysanthemum Festival.
You should appreciate His Majesty
for his grace.
Now that they choose to share the debt,
from now on,
you are their backer.
True.
This is an investment.
However, no one truly understands
what the treasury bonds mean.
If national prospect
is related to currency,
it means what wealth holds
has far surpassed the limitations
in the past.
Xian,
I have been pondering what you said.
I doubt that national prospect alone
can affect the Qing State
and its wealth.
There must be more connections
between them.
Due to His Majesty's favor for you,
those merchants chose to believe
in the treasury bonds
and the outlook
of the Imperial Treasury.
In fact, what they value isn't only you,
but also His Majesty,
royal credibility,
and the Qing State's credibility.
Exactly.
The amount of money is limited.
However, the Qing State's credibility
is the base of its currency.
That's right.
It doesn't just apply to the Qing State.
The credibility of Northern Qi
also represents its own wealth.
In short, state credibility
equals its wealth.
State credibility
is the wealth
and the base of its currency.
But what's missing between them?
Currency.
Credibility.
Let's go out
and let him figure it out himself.
Currency.
Wealth.
Credibility.
Currency.
What's wrong with Sizhe?
He's discovered a new world.
He is certainly a genius
in commerce.
Both of you are geniuses.
We are different.
I have a special memory.
That's considered cheating.
If we were to switch with each other,
at least I'm not as insightful as he is
in commerce.
He's better than me.
That's good.
Wan'er,
I'm sorry.
What's wrong?
We might need to leave Mount Cang soon.
Of course.
His Majesty is waiting for you
to attend the Chrysanthemum Festival.
I have prepared for so long.
But he simply could make it happen
with a word.
The Emperor
has always been the center of the state.
When the Chrysanthemum Festival is over,
let's go to Jiangnan.
Am I tagging along too?
My mother established
the Three Great Workshops in Jiangnan.
Up to this day,
it's still the foundation
of the Imperial Treasury.
These are the traces she left
in this world.
I think
we should go
and check them out together.
If state credibility
is connected to currency,
to maintain the balance between them,
we need a shop.
But I have never seen one before.
What should I name this shop?
Get a hand cannon
and practice aiming.
Your hands are steady.
You have potential in this.
Protecting Fan Xian
is a secret.
Do you want me to protect Xian
from a grandmaster?
No,
you have to kill him.
Kill a grandmaster.
It could also be me.
How much longer
are they going to stand there?
If you disturb them,
I will poison you.
Do you think
Mr. Wu would show up today?
Whether or not he shows up,
just forget about the spar.
You are no match for him.
What I care about isn't the result.
You are a martial artist.
You should know that.
I'm not a martial artist.
What are you, then?
I'm his master.
Do you see him as your disciple
or your son?
It seems that Mr. Wu
won't show up today.
I will head back to the Capital first.
Please be careful.
If Wuzhu is proven to be the murderer,
no one will survive.
Be it a disciple or a son,
does that matter?
What's wrong?
What did you see?
Nothing.
Good work.
What is this?
No... Nothing.
I saw it.
You bought a hand cannon.
That's right.
Did anyone bully you?
No.
It's just my interest.
I see.
Just be careful when you use it.
Where is Sizhe?
He has been acting strangely.
There he is.
Xian.
Ruoruo.
I'm coming.
Time to go.
It is.
We have been waiting for you.
It's not that, Ruoruo.
I'm saying
that I'm heading to Northern Qi.
Northern Qi?
I have discussed it with Xian.
Mother agrees too.
Have you figured out
how to lead the commercial business?
I'm working on it.
It's getting clearer.
I have been thinking
about state credibility
and currency base you said.
I feel
there needs to be a shop
to maintain the balance between them.
Opening the shop in the Qing States
is like sending myself to death.
It can only be in Northern Qi.
Northern Qi has just lost in the war
and is waiting for a revival.
This presents us
with a good opportunity.
If I can seize it,
this shop will be unprecedented,
and I will be the pioneer.
On a small scale,
I can make some money.
On a large scale,
the prospect of Northern Qi
will be under my thumb.
Have you come up with a name yet?
Yes, I did.
Give me some idea.
You see,
a shop selling rice grain
is called a rice store,
and a shop selling fabric
is called a fabric store.
Since this shop is related to money,
it's too straightforward
if we call it a money store.
It's crude.
Money is silver, right?
So
let's call it Fan Store.
Then why did you mention silver?
[*Silver store literally means "bank"]
No.
Here's what I think.
We are the pioneers in this business.
The Fan family
must be remembered for this,
right?
Maybe you should refine the name.
If Fan Store isn't good,
let's call it
Xian Store?
Ruo Store?
Zhe Store?
Forget it.
I will think about it on the way.
Xian, you know what?
I'm so thrilled.
I feel like
I have finally figured out
what I'm living for.
That's your life's purpose.
Right, I found my life's purpose!
Mr. Fan,
it's the Imperial Guards.
They are here to block my way.
Black Cavalries, stand by.
Always ready to charge.
No...
They are the Imperial Guards.
The Emperor's troop.
Don't worry.
Black Cavalries is the strongest troop.
We will never lose.
No.
That's not my concern.
What Wang means is,
attacking the Imperial Guards
is a serious crime.
As per Mr. Chen's order,
Black Cavalries obey the military order
by Inspector
while in Mount Cang.
Someone is coming.
Isn't this an old acquaintance of mine?
Mr. Fan,
it has been a long time.
Commander Gong, you guard the palace.
Why did you leave the Capital today?
His Majesty instructed me
for a task outside the palace.
I wish you a smooth journey,
Commander Gong.
Why? Should I make way for you?
According to His Majesty's order,
please come with us, Mr. Fan.
You reached here
right after I came down from Mount Cang.
You certainly get news quickly.
I only understand the order.
I don't know anything else.
In that case,
please show me the way.
We will follow behind you.
The troop doesn't have to tag along.
Just you, Mr. Fan.
You said it's an order from His Majesty.
Do you have the imperial edict?
This is small.
His Majesty said,
"Don't be
wasteful."
Well, His Majesty
is indeed frugal.
[Follow Gong Dian]
Mr. Fan,
please.
this is where the imperial family
admired flowers in previous years.
[Hanging Temple]
Built between cliffs,
hovering in midair.
The legendary
Hanging Temple.
[Hanging Temple]
This is the oldest temple
in the Qing State.
Legend has it
that it was built brick by brick
by ascetics who believed
in the Divine Temple.
All temples in the world
are set up
to worship the legendary Divine Temple.
But only the genuine Divine Temple
is unique.
Still, the power of the mass
can be immeasurable.
Mr. Fan, you value
humans more.
Of course.
That's why we call it the human world.
The Chrysanthemum Festival
is in a few days.
Our task
is to carry all of these
up there.
What am I needed here for?
His Majesty said
you have to carry
these pots up there by yourself.
What's so special about them?
I don't know.
I'm only following orders.
Is it held every three years?
It has become a tradition.
This is the very opportunity
for those with evil will.
♪ The youth raises his head ♪
♪ As he moves toward his moon ♪
♪ People tease him for being delusional ♪
♪ Wondering why he is so unconventional ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ How could it remain unstained? ♪
♪ If silver tael has a value ♪
♪ Who can truly be carefree? ♪
♪ All of you are right ♪
♪ He said: "Please" ♪
♪ "Make way" ♪
♪ "Let me drink until I drop" ♪
♪ On the court ♪
♪ I recite several verses ♪
♪ Let me wear a white robe ♪
♪ And cross the alley
filled with insanity ♪
♪ To scoop up the moon's reflection
in the muddy pond ♪
♪ Sirs, please forgive me ♪
♪ Your words of advice ♪
♪ I understand,
but I don't want to pretend ♪
♪ People search for the golden land ♪
♪ While I search for the moon ♪
♪ Why should we travel together? ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ Remarkably worldly-wise
yet hopelessly romantic ♪
♪ Know what you love ♪
♪ Don't change ♪
♪ If one has witnessed
both light and shadow ♪
♪ Yet retains their innocence ♪
♪ They shall be cloaked in moonlight ♪
♪ As they journey through the night ♪